Julian F. Smith

Ingleside, Texas 78362 | Phone: (361) 246-0493 | Email: smith.julian.f@gmail.com Portfolio: https://juliansmith.dev | GitHub: https://github.com/Gamesmith9000 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/julian-f-smith

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a desire to help others through technology. Interested in the interaction of analytical and artistic thinking. Detail-oriented, with a history of attention to detail. Excels at problem solving, research, and possess a strong skill base acquired through the completion of a full stack web development program. Excellent interpersonal communication skills and team collaborator that works well on team-based projects as well as independently.

Technical Skills

C# | CSS5 | HTML3 | JavaScript | Ruby | SASS | Bootstrap | JQuery | React | Ruby on Rails | Bitbucket | Git | GitHub | SourceTree | Heroku | Netlify | PostgreSQL | Amazon AWS (S3) | Google Firebase (Realtime Database) | Google Maps API | Unity Engine

Projects

Flixter | GitHub: https://github.com/Gamesmith9000/Flixter/

Live Site: https://flixter-julian-smith.herokuapp.com/

A two-sided video lesson marketplace. Includes separate experiences for users and instructors, the capacity for credit card transactions, and uploading of user-generated video. Served as the sole developer.

Technologies & Languages Used: CSS3, HTML5, Ruby, SASS, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Git, GitHub,

Heroku, Bootstrap, Amazon S3, Font Awesome, Stripe

Grammable | GitHub: https://github.com/Gamesmith9000/Grammable/

Live Site: https://grammable-julian-smith.herokuapp.com/

This application is similar to Instagram and was created using test-driven development. Includes user validation and image uploading. Served as the sole developer.

Technologies & Languages Used: CSS3, HTML5, Ruby, SASS, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Git, GitHub, Heroku, Bootstrap, Amazon S3

Bro Chess | GitHub: https://github.com/BroCode2020/bro-chess/ | Live Site: https://bro-chess.herokuapp.com/ A chess game team project using the agile methodology. Employed extensive use of version control, code review, and test-driven development. It also includes drag-and-drop functionality, SVG graphics, and Google Firebase integration for real-time updates.

Technologies & Languages Used: CSS3, HTML5, Javascript, Ruby, SASS, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Git, GitHub, Heroku, Bootstrap, JQuery, Google Realtime Database

Experience

Freelance Web Developer

Various Organizations; Remote

2020 - Present

Plan and deliver software platforms used across multiple products and organizational units. Implemented a simple framework to be utilized by clients for content creation and management, utilizing Ruby on Rails, Sass, and JavaScript.

Momentum Hospitality, Inc.

2016 - Present

Front Desk Supervisor | Fairfield by Marriott | Rockport, TX | 2019 - Present

Coordinate with the general manager and implement new standard operating procedures. Write utility scripts for the FOSSE Property Management System (which is run on SecureCRT, which allows scripting) to save

time for employees. Create and maintain numerous spreadsheets for inventory, maintenance, front desk, and management. Transfer hotel documents to cloud-based storage for uniform access across all devices. Train new employees in hotel procedures and FOSSE Property Management System.

Front Desk Agent | Microtel Inn & Suites | Aransas Pass, TX | 2017 - 2019

Assisted with reopening the hotel after Hurricane Harvey. Coordinated with workers and contractors. Prior to opening to the public, worked at the front desk and helped with maintenance while hosting workers tasked with restoring local power lines. Conducted troubleshooting for the Synxis Property Management System.

Promoted to a supervisor role at Fairfield by Marriott.

Front Desk Agent | Fairfield Inn & Suites | Rockport, TX | 2016 - 2017

Combined and modified two separate sources to create standard shift checklists. Produced tailor-made, eco-friendly version of the contingency reports. Created a utility script for the FOSSE Property Management System to automate printing reports.

Night Auditor | Hampton Inn & Suites | Rockport, TX | 2014 - 2016

Transmitted electronic credit payment data, utilizing a separate verification service. Allocated housekeeping room assignments. Created custom spreadsheets for room types and counts. Built custom printouts that assured fair and balanced distribution.

• Garnered a promotion from employers, working at the newly established Fairfield Inn & Suites.

Education

Coding Bootcamp Certificate - University of Texas

97 hours of completed coursework towards Bachelor of Arts in Anthropology - Texas A&M University